<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Weiyu Chen&#39;s Personal Website</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
        <description>Recent content on Weiyu Chen&#39;s Personal Website</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Weiyu Chen</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/</guid>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-me&#34;&gt;About Me
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hello! I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;strong&gt;Weiyu Chen&lt;/strong&gt;, a fourth-year computer science student at &lt;strong&gt;Fuzhou University&lt;/strong&gt;. I have been admitted to the MSc in &lt;strong&gt;Engineering in Robotics and Intelligent Systems&lt;/strong&gt; at &lt;strong&gt;The University of Hong Kong&lt;/strong&gt;, beginning in the fall of 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interests&lt;/strong&gt;: Recommender Systems, Medical Image Analysis, Face Recognition &amp;amp; Person Re-ID&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Career Goals&lt;/strong&gt;: To publish high-quality research papers in reputable journals and conferences while pursuing a master&amp;rsquo;s degree in computer science, with a focus on advancing my expertise in deep learning and its applications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;education&#34;&gt;Education
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B.S. in Computer Science&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Fuzhou University&lt;/strong&gt;, 2021 - 2025
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Relevant Courses: Advanced Artificial Intelligence, Technology of Data Mining, Pattern Recognition, Computer Graphics, Computer Organization and Architecture, Operating Systems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Awards and Honors:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Awarded the &lt;strong&gt;Second-Class Scholarship&lt;/strong&gt; of the university&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Twice awarded the &lt;strong&gt;Third-Class Scholarship&lt;/strong&gt; of the School&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Received the &lt;strong&gt;Progress Award&lt;/strong&gt; once&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recognized as an &lt;strong&gt;Outstanding Individual&lt;/strong&gt; in the College for three academic years (2021, 2022, 2023)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;research-and-publications&#34;&gt;Research and Publications
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;masked-theme-specific-named-entity-recognition-assisted-with-large-language-models&#34;&gt;Masked Theme-Specific Named Entity Recognition Assisted with Large Language Models
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;: Co-authored a paper that proposes an effective two-stage approach for named entity recognition using masked theme-specific methods associated with large language models. This approach leverages an unsupervised mechanism rather than a supervised one, enhancing the efficiency of NER tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Citation&lt;/strong&gt;: Ying Zhao, &lt;strong&gt;Weiyu Chen&lt;/strong&gt;, Longlong Liao, et al., &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Masked Theme-Specific Named Entity Recognition Assisted with Large Language Models,&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;2024 IEEE International Conference on Computing (ICOCO 2024)&lt;/em&gt;, Accepted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;brain-tumor-diagnosis-with-deep-separable-convolutional-networks&#34;&gt;Brain Tumor Diagnosis with Deep Separable Convolutional Networks
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;: Researched and developed a model for brain tumor classification, achieving a &lt;strong&gt;97.41%&lt;/strong&gt; accuracy rate using deep separable convolutional networks and attention mechanisms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Citation&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;Weiyu Chen&lt;/strong&gt;, Peiyao Sun, and Yujia Zhang, &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;A Brain Tumor Diagnosis Approach Based on Deep Separable Convolutional Networks and Attention Mechanisms,&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Applied and Computational Engineering&lt;/em&gt;, vol. 67, no. 1, pp. 60-69, Jul. 2024, doi: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.54254/2755-2721/67/20240629&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;10.54254/2755-2721/67/20240629&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;projects&#34;&gt;Projects
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;project-1-neural-graph-collaborative-filtering-based-parking-space-recommendation-system&#34;&gt;Project 1: Neural Graph Collaborative Filtering-based Parking Space Recommendation System
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;: This project focused on developing a parking space recommendation system that utilizes &lt;strong&gt;neural graph collaborative filtering&lt;/strong&gt; technology. By integrating user data and parking behavior patterns into a graph database, the system provides personalized parking space suggestions, enhancing user convenience and optimizing parking space usage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technologies Used&lt;/strong&gt;: PyTorch, Neo4j, Pandas, Flask+Vue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contribution&lt;/strong&gt;: As the &lt;strong&gt;project leader&lt;/strong&gt;, I oversaw the development process from initial design to final implementation. My responsibilities included guiding the architecture of the system, managing the development team, and ensuring that the recommendation algorithm met the project&amp;rsquo;s objectives and performance criteria.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;project-2-video-identity-recognition&#34;&gt;Project 2: Video Identity Recognition
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;: Engineered an advanced identity recognition system that leverages real-time video streams, utilizing the &lt;strong&gt;YOLOv7 model&lt;/strong&gt; for precise human detection and subsequent image segmentation. The system combines state-of-the-art &lt;strong&gt;Face Recognition&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Person Re-ID algorithms&lt;/strong&gt; to achieve a remarkable identification accuracy of &lt;strong&gt;98%&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Core Idea&lt;/strong&gt;: Integration of Face Recognition and Person Re-identification&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contribution&lt;/strong&gt;: Key innovations include the implementation of &lt;strong&gt;standing detection&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;specifically delineated check-in zones&lt;/strong&gt; to mitigate interference from unauthorized entities and minimize erroneous operations. Plans are underway to incorporate this system into the &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Multimodal Big Data-Driven Platform for Research Efficiency Analysis&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;, aiming to facilitate a non-contact, camera-based authentication module in laboratory settings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;project-3-traffic-scene-object-detection-based-on-mmdetection&#34;&gt;Project 3: Traffic Scene Object Detection Based on MMDetection
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;: The core objective of the project is to accurately and comprehensively detect all specified objects in traffic scene images by making adjustments in areas such as model selection, data augmentation, and loss function optimization.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;project-4-single-page-application-for-object-detection-model-evaluation-and-result-display-based-on-pyscriptvue&#34;&gt;Project 4: Single-Page Application for Object Detection Model Evaluation and Result Display Based on PyScript+Vue
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;: Developed a pure front-end single-page application that uses PyScript to execute Python code and implements the mAP value evaluation function of the object detection model.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Designed System&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://icnc-fskd.fzu.edu.cn/hwd/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;internship-experience&#34;&gt;Internship Experience
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;ai-development-engineer-data-security-product-department-china-telecom-fufu-information-technology-co-ltd&#34;&gt;AI Development Engineer, Data Security Product Department, China Telecom FuFu Information Technology Co., Ltd.
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Duration&lt;/strong&gt;: July 2024 - November 2024&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Researched the architecture of the User &amp;amp; Entity Behavior Analytics (UEBA) system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generated pre-training data for large language model-based Q&amp;amp;A systems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expanded knowledge of common machine learning algorithms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;contact&#34;&gt;Contact
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Email&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;mailto:chenweiyu0315@foxmail.com&#34; &gt;chenweiyu0315@foxmail.com&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;mailto:durian_cwy@163.com&#34; &gt;durian_cwy@163.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
